<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="getting_started">
  <title>Getting Started</title>

  <para>
    Welcome to EdgeGuard!
  </para>

  <para>
    This section will help you decide where to install EdgeGuard, connect it properly, and start the setup wizard.
  </para>

  <sect1 id="getting_started_installation">
    <title>Installation</title>

    <sect2 id="getting_started_installation_plug">
      <title>Where to install</title>

      <para>
	EdgeGuard will fit into many network configurations. There are three basic configurations we will discuss here.
      </para>

      <figure id="getting_started_network1">
	<title>EdgeGuard as a Router</title>
	<mediaobject>
	  <imageobject>
	    <imagedata fileref="figure/gettingstarted/network1.png" />
	  </imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>
	Commonly, EdgeGuard is installed as a router/firewall. You will need to plug your Internet device (modem, T1 router, etc) into the external port of the &eg;. You will also need to plug in the internal port of &eg; into the main internal switch. If you have a <glossterm linkend="gloss_dmz">DMZ</glossterm> (public subnet) you may plug that into the third port (not labeled "External" or "External") on the &eg;. If you wish to have a private subnet on the internal subnet (ie <constant>192.168.x.x</constant>, <constant>10.x.x.x</constant>), you will need to install the Network Sharing Software Appliance and enable <glossterm linkend="gloss_nat">NAT</glossterm> (Network Address Translation). You can read more on this under <xref linkend="nat_tran"/>.
      </para>

      <figure id="getting_started_network2">
	<title>EdgeGuard as a Bridge</title>
	<mediaobject>
	  <imageobject>
	    <imagedata fileref="figure/gettingstarted/network2.png" />
	  </imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
      </figure>
      
      <para>
	If you already have a router/firewall and wish to keep it installed, you may simply install EdgeGuard between the firewall and the main internal switch. Simply connect the external port of the &eg; directly in the internal port on your firewall, and the internal port on the &eg; to the main internal switch which connects your host. In this scenario, the &eg; will function as a bridge. You do not need to change your default route (gateway) on any of the machines behind the firewall, nor change the routes on your router.
      </para>

      <figure id="getting_started_network3">
	<title>EdgeGuard as a Bridge</title>
	<mediaobject>
	  <imageobject>
	    <imagedata fileref="figure/gettingstarted/network3.png" />
	  </imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
      </figure>
      
      <para>
	You may also install the &eg; as a bridge between the firewall and the Internet device. This is not recommended because the <glossterm linkend="gloss_dos">Denial-of-Service</glossterm> protection within &eg; will not be able to differentiate between the internal machines behind your firewall. Also, the reports produced by EdgeGuard (<xref linkend="reporting_tran"/>) will not be able to differentiate between internal machines behind your firewall.
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="getting_started_installation_quickstart">
      <title>QuickStart</title>
      <para>
	Once you have decided how you will configure EdgeGuard follow the QuickStart guide included with your appliance to setup the appliance. The QuickStart guide can also downloaded from <ulink  url="http://metavize.com/docs/quickstart/">http://metavize.com/docs/quickstart/</ulink>
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="getting_started_installation_interfaces">
      <title>Interfaces</title>
      <para id="getting_started_interfaces"  xreflabel="Network Interfaces">
	The &eg; has several interfaces. The internal, external and DMZ interfaces do not need separate IP addresses or IP address spaces. In the default configuration they are all bridged and share the same IP address and address space. Traffic is transparently captured and forwarded to the correct interface. If multiple address spaces are bridged you can specify "aliases" in the network settings <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddraliases"/>.  
      </para>
      
      <para id="getting_started_internalip" xreflabel="Internal IP Address">
	When Network Sharing is installed and NAT is enabled, the internal interface has its own address and address space. The address will serve as the default route (gateway) for internal machines. In this case, the external and DMZ interfaces are still bridged and share the same address space.
      </para>

      <para id="getting_started_interfaces_vpn" xreflabel="VPN Interface">
	VPN can also create virtual interfaces. This is covered in <xref linkend="openvpn_tran"/>.
      </para>

  </sect1>
</chapter>

