<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>Metavize EdgeGuard is a comprehensive, software-based security
  solution. EdgeGuard can be installed in minutes, and drops seamlessly into
  existing infrastructure behind or in place of your firewall. EdgeGuard
  simplifies the complexity of securing the network, and allows you to
  install, deploy, configure, manage and generate reports across a wide
  selection of point solutions from a single point.</para>

  <para>The user-friendly management GUI is designed to resemble a virtual
  rack, as shown in <xref linkend="figure1_1" /></para>

  <para></para>

  <figure>
    <title id="figure1_1">This is an Image title</title>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="figure/someKDEPicture.png" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <para>This is a pararaph, after the image was used. The administration said
  that suspending the rules would reduce rebuilding costs and help open
  opportunities for minority-owned companies, but critics said it would result
  in lower pay for workers.</para>

  <para>Members of Congress were first informed of the decision at a White
  House meeting with Chief of Staff Andrew Card on Wednesday morning.</para>

  <para>The decision, which means that workers will get wages closer to what
  they were making before the hurricane, was met with approval by Republicans
  and Democrats, many of whom felt that out-of-state workers were descending
  on hurricane-ravaged areas and working for a fraction of a living
  wage.</para>

  <para>The Davis-Bacon Act, which guarantees the wage levels, was suspended
  Sept. 8. It will be reinstated Nov. 8.</para>

  <para>Rep. Steven LaTourette, R-Ohio, who attended the White House meeting,
  told CNN that the situation was unacceptable.</para>

  <para>"The danger we have in the Gulf Coast in general is profiteering. When
  you have these large contracts and again, when you suspend some protections
  ... it appears you can pay people whatever you want to pay and the rest of
  the money goes into the profit column of the corporation," he said.</para>

  <para>Rep. George Miller, D-Calif., who has led his party's charge against
  the Davis-Bacon suspension, said in an interview with CNN, "At least those
  wages will be protected where federal money is involved, and that's very
  important to the economy of that region. This is why we couldn't understand
  how the president could take such a callous</para>

  <para></para>

  <para>Now, here is an example of a numbered list</para>

  <para></para>

  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>This is some item</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>This is Another item from the list</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>This will be a item in the list, but will have new lines</para>

      <para>Not sure if that makes sense</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>This continues the list</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>

  <para>Now, we're done that numbered list. Lets move on to an un-numbered
  list</para>

  <para></para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>The first item</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Yet another</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>And a third</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>Cool. Now, how about a "variable" list. Not sure what that
  is...</para>

  <para></para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>This is from the var list</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>I think the idea is that this is a "large" list entry, which may
        have lots of junk associated with each entry. As such, I'm testing it
        now to see what happens when I put-in a lot of text. Laa sdf dsf fds
        dsf sdf dfs dfs dfs sdf dfs sdf v sefg bfdx gbndf ghbdf gybdr fghb
        tfgb yhdrg fhdrt byhd rtfvhg bdrtfy hbrdr tfcgfy bhg trffcvgy d5rt fy
        ge45drt yfg ed4r5tge 4d5rtf g</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Odd, I cannot fugure this out</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>I think the idea is that this is a "large" list entry, which may
        have lots of junk associated with each entry. As such, I'm testing it
        now to see what happens when I put-in a lot of text. Laa sdf dsf fds
        dsf sdf dfs dfs dfs sdf dfs sdf v sefg bfdx gbndf ghbdf gybdr fghb
        tfgb yhdrg fhdrt byhd rtfvhg bdrtfy hbrdr tfcgfy bhg trffcvgy d5rt fy
        ge45drt yfg ed4r5tge 4d5rtf g</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <itemizedlist></itemizedlist>

  <para>Whatever. Here is some more CNN stuff</para>

  <para>He wrote officials that $20,850 contributed in 2000 and 2001 was not
  reported anywhere. Another $17,300 was included in the defense fund's
  quarterly report but not in DeLay's 2000 annual financial disclosure report
  -- a separate requirement.</para>

  <para>Other donations were understated as totaling $2,800, when the figure
  should have been $4,450.</para>

  <para>It was during that period that DeLay was the subject of several House
  ethics investigations.</para>

  <para>DeLay, R-Texas, stepped aside as House majority leader -- at least
  temporarily -- after he was indicted on a felony charge September 28 in a
  Texas campaign fund-raising investigation.</para>

  <para>He has since been charged a second time in the same case.</para>

  <para>On October 13 DeLay wrote the clerk of the House, Jeff Trandahl, that
  his first inkling of inconsistencies in his disclosures came last
  February.</para>

  <para>"I brought this matter -- which I discovered on my own -- to the
  attention of the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to alert the
  chairman and ranking member," DeLay said in his letter.</para>

  <para>"Upon learning of these accounting irregularities, I immediately
  requested that the trust undergo a full and complete audit from its June
  2000 inception through 2004 to determine if any additional accountancy
  problems existed with the trust."</para>

  <para>The audit confirmed the unreported donations and the other errors,
  DeLay said.</para>

  <para></para>

  <para></para>

  <para>The following items comprise the Virtual Rack Interface:</para>

  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>The Virtual Rack</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Software Appliance. This displays security modules that have been
      downloaded and installed as Software Appliances.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para></para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>

  <para></para>

  <para></para>

  <simpara>fsddsfjksdfjdsf sdf sdffsd sdf dfs dsf dfss df asd fafsd asdf asdf
  asdf fsddsfjksdfjdsf sdf sdffsd sdf dfs dsf dfss df asd fafsd asdf asdf asdf
  fsddsfjksdfjdsf sdf sdffsd sdf dfs dsf dfss df asd fafsd asdf asdf asdf fsd
  fsdsdfsdfsdf 443 er df 564 egrsd gd h ert gdf fsd fsdsdfsdfsdf 443 er df 564
  egrsd jhkhk fsd fsdsdfsdfsdf 443 er df 564 egrsd fsd fsdsdfsdfsdf 443 er df
  564 egrsd jkhjhhj hjkjjkh hhkfsd fsdsdfsdfsdf 443 er df 564 egrsd fsd
  fsdsdfsdfsdf 443 er df 564 egrsd</simpara>
</chapter>