<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="firewall_tran">

  <title>Firewall</title>

  <!-- Note that the "introduction" is not within a Section.  This is
       the convention we'll use
  -->
  <para>
    The Firewall Appliance is identified by the
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="figure/firewall/firewall_tran_icon.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
    symbol.  If the Firewall Appliance is not installed, please refer to <xref linkend="introduction_ui_appliance"/> for installation instructions.
  </para>
  <para>
    As its name implies, the Firewall Appliance provides traditional firewall functionality, blocking traffic based on rules.  Rules are based on a combination of protocol, source and destination.  Unlike traditional firewalls but like many other &eg; Software Appliances, the Firewall can simply monitor (rather than block) traffic of interest and log events (see <xref linkend="firewall_tran_eventlog"/>.)
  </para>

  <sect1 id="firewall_tran_adminui">
    <title>Administrative Interface</title>

    <para>
      The interface for the Firewall Appliance is presented as three tabs.  The first two tabs, discussed in <xref linkend="firewall_tran_blockpass"/> and <xref linkend="firewall_tran_general"/>, allow the administrator to configure the behavior of the firewall appliance.  The last tab allows administrators to view firewall events (see <xref linkend="introduction_ui_appliance_event_log"/>).
    </para>
  

    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="firewall_tran_blockpass">
      <title>Block/Pass List</title>
      <para>
        The Block/Pass List, shown in <xref linkend="firewall_tran_blockpass_figure"/>, is an ordered list of rules.  Rules may select (<quote>match</quote>) a connection.  If a given rule does select a connection, the connection is either blocked or passed (depending on the value of <guilabel>action</guilabel>).
      </para>
      <figure id="firewall_tran_blockpass_figure">
        <title>Block/Pass List Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/firewall/firewall_blockpass.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        As new connections are made, the Firewall Appliance evaluates its rules in order.  The relative order of the rules can be determined by observing the <guilabel>#</guilabel> column as seen in  <xref linkend="firewall_tran_blockpass_figure"/>.  The Firewall Appliance attempts to match the connection to each rule based on the rule's criteria (more on that in a moment).  If the connection matches, the <guilabel>action</guilabel> specified is taken.  Should no rule match a given connection, the default action is taken (see <xref linkend="firewall_tran_general"/>).
      </para>
      <para>
        Rules match connections based on six (6) criteria.  These criteria are as follows.  Note that the term <quote>source</quote> means <quote>machine which initiated the connection</quote> and <quote>destination</quote> means <quote>machine receiving the connect requests</quote>.

        <variablelist id="firewall_tran_blockpass_matchingcriteria">
          <title>Firewall Rule Matching Criteria</title>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>traffic type</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The <guilabel>traffic type</guilabel> criteria selects the protocol to be matched.  Valid values are <glossterm linkend="gloss_tcp">TCP</glossterm>, <glossterm linkend="gloss_udp">UDP</glossterm>, or <glossterm linkend="gloss_ping">PING</glossterm> (as well as a few combinations thereof). 
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>direction</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The <guilabel>direction</guilabel> criteria defines the location of the source and destination relative to the protected network.  <guilabel>Inbound</guilabel> means the sorce is outside the protected network, and the destination within.  <guilabel>Outbound</guilabel> means the destination is outside the protected network, and the source within.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>source address</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                This property selects the <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of the connection source.  Valid values are in <link linkend="appendix_syntax_ipmatcher">IP Matcher</link> format. 
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>destination address</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                This property selects the <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of the connection destination.  Valid values are in <link linkend="appendix_syntax_ipmatcher">IP Matcher</link> format. 
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>source port</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                This property selects the <glossterm linkend="gloss_port">port</glossterm> of the connection source.  Valid values are in <link linkend="appendix_syntax_portmatcher">Port Matcher</link> format.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>destination port</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                This property selects the <glossterm linkend="gloss_port">port</glossterm> of the connection destination.  Valid values are in <link linkend="appendix_syntax_portmatcher">Port Matcher</link> format.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>          
        </variablelist>
      </para>
    </sect2>
  
  
    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="firewall_tran_general">
      <title>General Settings</title>
      <para>
        The General Settings tab contains only a single property, as can be seen in <xref linkend="firewall_tran_general_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="firewall_tran_general_figure">
        <title>General Settings Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/firewall/firewall_general.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        Note that the <guilabel>Default Action</guilabel> only applies when a given connection fails to match any rule in the <link linkend="firewall_tran_blockpass">BLock/Pass List</link>.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  
  
  
    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="firewall_tran_eventlog">
      <title>Event Log</title>
      <para>
        The Events tab contents is shown in <xref linkend="firewall_tran_eventlog_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="firewall_tran_eventlog_figure">
        <title>Event Log Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/firewall/firewall_eventlog.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Events Tab is another implementation of an Event Log, as described in <xref linkend="introduction_ui_appliance_event_log"/>.  
      </para>         
    </sect2>     
  </sect1>


  <sect1 id="firewall_tran_qa">
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaset>  
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>Where is the Q&amp;A list?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            TODO Someone needs to write it.  Some good things would be Network/Netmask syntax for matching all networks, a reminder of the "any" syntax, etc.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
    </qandaset>
  </sect1>    

</chapter>
