<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="ids_tran">

  <title>Intrusion Prevention</title>
  <para>
    The Intrusion Prevention Appliance is identified by the
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="figure/ids/ids_tran_icon.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
    symbol.  If the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is not installed, please refer to <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances"/> for installation instructions.
  </para>
  <para>
    As its name implies, the Intrusion Prevention Appliance serves to prevent known malicious exploits from entering your protected network.  It is based on technology from <ulink  url="http://www.snort.org/">Snort.org</ulink>.  The Snort community maintains data on known exploits, and produces lists of <emphasis>signatures</emphasis> for these exploits.  The Intrusion Prevention Appliance then interprets these lists to protect your network.  Note that with the exception of the <xref linkend="ids_tran_eventlog"/>, configuration of the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is an advanced topic.
  </para>

  <sect1 id="ids_tran_adminui">
    <title>Administrative Interface</title>

    <para>
      The interface for the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is presented as three tabs.  The first two tabs, discussed in <xref linkend="ids_tran_rule"/> and <xref linkend="ids_tran_varlist"/>, allow the administrator to configure <emphasis>advanced</emphasis> settings.  The last tab, <xref linkend="ids_tran_eventlog"/>, allows administrators to view intrusion scanning events (see <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances_eventlog"/>).
    </para>
  

    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="ids_tran_rule">
      <title>Rule List</title>
      <para>
        The interface for the Rule List tab of the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is seen in <xref linkend="ids_tran_rule_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="ids_tran_rule_figure">
        <title>Rule List Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/ids/ids_rulelist.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        As stated previously, the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is based on technology from <ulink  url="http://www.snort.org/">Snort.org</ulink>.  <emphasis>Adding or modifying rules in the syntax defined by Snort.org is a advanced topic,</emphasis> and will not be covered in this manual.
      </para>
      <para>
        All that the average Administrator may want to do is to alter the <guilabel>block</guilabel> or <guilabel>log</guilabel> values for a given rule.  The <guilabel>block</guilabel> field causes the Intrusion Prevention Appliance to block traffic matching the given pattern.  The <guilabel>log</guilabel> field causes the Intrusion Prevention Appliance to log traffic which matches the rule's pattern.
        <tip>
          <para>
            The Intrusion Prevention Appliance ships with a default set of rules set to <guilabel>block</guilabel> harmful traffic.  You should only disable such a rule if a unique software you use happens to collide with a rule.
          </para>
        </tip> 
      </para>
    </sect2>


    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="ids_tran_varlist">
      <title>Variable List</title>
      <para>
        The interface for the Variable List tab of the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is seen in <xref linkend="ids_tran_varlist_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="ids_tran_varlist_figure">
        <title>Variable Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/ids/ids_varlist.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        As stated previously, the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is based on technology from <ulink  url="http://www.snort.org/">Snort.org</ulink>.  <emphasis>Modifying the variables is a advanced topic,</emphasis> and will not be covered in this manual.
      </para>
    </sect2>
    

    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="ids_tran_eventlog">
      <title>Rule List</title>
      <para>
        The Events tab contents is shown in <xref linkend="ids_tran_eventlog_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="ids_tran_eventlog_figure">
        <title>Event Log Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/ids/ids_eventlog.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Events Tab is another implementation of an Event Log, as described in <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances_eventlog"/>.  The complete list of columns and their meaning is as follows.
        <variablelist>
          <title>Events Tab</title>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>timestamp</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The time the event took place
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>action</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action which took place (e.g. <constant>block</constant>).
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>client</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The client <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of the traffic.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>reason for action</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The rule number which cause the event to take place.  All Intrusion Prevention Appliance rules are numbered, as shown in <xref linkend="ids_tran_rule_figure"/>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>direction</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The direction (<constant>inbound</constant> or <constant>outbound</constant>) of the traffic.  Most Intrusion Prevention Appliance rules only apply to the <constant>inbound</constant> (into the protected network) direction.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>server</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The intended server <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of the traffic.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>                                                                
        </variablelist>        
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="ids_tran_qaXXX">
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaset>  
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>Where is the Q&amp;A list?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            TODO Someone needs to write it.  
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
    </qandaset>
  </sect1>  

</chapter>
