<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="reporting_tran">
  <title>EdgeReports</title>

  <para>
    The EdgeReports Appliance is identified by the
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="figure/reporting/reporting_tran_icon.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>

    symbol.  If the EdgeReports Appliance is not installed, please refer to <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances"/> for installation instructions.
  </para>


  <sect1 id="reporting_tran_adminui">
    <title>Administrative Interface</title>

    <para>
      The interface for the EdgeReports Appliance is presented as three tabs.  The first tab, <xref linkend="reporting_tran_viewreports"/>, is a convenience which launches a web browser to view the current reports.  The second tab, <xref linkend="reporting_tran_emailrcpts"/>, is used to maintain a list of administrators who will receive daily reports via email.  The last tab, <xref linkend="reporting_tran_ipaddrmap"/>, is used to provide host names for <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP addresses</glossterm>.
    </para>  
    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="reporting_tran_viewreports">
      <title>View Reports</title>
      <para>
        This tab is a convenience to launch a web browser to view the reports.
      </para>
      <figure id="reporting_tran_viewreports_figure">
        <title>View Reports Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/reporting/reporting_viewreports.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <note>
        <para>
          For security reasons, Administrators connected directly via keyboard, monitor, and mouse to the &eg; machine cannot launch a browser.
        </para>
      </note>
    </sect2>
  
    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="reporting_tran_emailrcpts">
      <title>Email Report Recipients</title>
      <para>
        The Email Report Recipients tab, as shown in <xref linkend="reporting_tran_emailrcpts_figure"/>, lets Administrators maintain the list of email addresses of users who will receive reports by email.
      </para>
      <figure id="reporting_tran_emailrcpts_figure">
        <title>Email Report Recipients Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/reporting/reporting_emailrcpts.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        To add an email address, push the add (plus) button, enter a valid email address in the <guilabel>Email Address</guilabel> field, and push the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  
    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="reporting_tran_ipaddrmap">
      <title>IP Address to User Map</title>
      <para>
        The <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP Address</glossterm> to User Map tab, as shown in <xref linkend="reporting_tran_ipaddrmap_figure"/>, lets administrators maintain the names of <glossterm linkend="gloss_static_ip">static IP addresses</glossterm>.  These names replace the IP addresses seen in the reports, to enhance readability.
      </para>
      <figure id="reporting_tran_ipaddrmap_figure">
        <title>IP Address to User Map Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/reporting/reporting_ipaddrmap.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        This applies for addresses in reports.  For external addresses (addresses outside the protected network), it is unlikely that you could (or should) configure all IP addresses.  However, for internal (protected) addresses configuring this panel makes reports more readable.
      </para>
      <para>
        If you are using <glossterm linkend="gloss_dhcp">DHCP</glossterm>, as discussed in <xref linkend="nat_tran_dhcp"/>, then you do not need to use this tab.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="reporting_tran_qa">
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaset>  
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>I'm not getting reports, yet I added my email address to the email list as shown in <xref linkend="reporting_tran_emailrcpts"/>?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            The most common error is to configure yet not turn-on the EdgeReports Appliance.  Please be sure that the EdgeReports Appliance is turned on (see <xref linkend="using_adminui"/> for a discussion of turning on/off appliances).
          <para>
            The next most common error is that the reports have yet to be emailed.  Reports are emailed on a daily basis, so you need to wait up to 24 hours to receive your first report email.
          </para>
          <para>
            If you have been using the &eg; for more than 24 hours, you need to check the global email settings.  Please refer to <xref linkend="config_tab_network_email"/> for help on these settings.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
    </qandaset>
  </sect1>     
  
</chapter>
