<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="upgrade_manager">
  <title>Upgrades</title>

  <para>
    The Upgrade Manager controls software updates and new features for your &eg;.  The Upgrade Manager is launched from the main Administrative Interface by pushing the <guilabel>Upgrade</guilabel> button as seen in <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_launch_upgrade_manager"/>.
  </para>
  <figure id="upgrade_manager_launch_upgrade_manager">
    <title>Launching the upgrade Manager</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="figure/upgrademngr/launch_upgrade.png" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>    
  <para>
    Please visit <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_manual"/> or more details on manually upgrading your &eg;.  To configure your &eg; for automatic upgrades, please refer to <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_automatic"/>.
  </para>

  <sect1 id="upgrade_manager_adminui">
    <title>Administrative Interface</title>
    <para>
      The Administrative Interface is divided into two sections.  The first section, covered in <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_manual"/>, discusses how to manually upgrade your &eg;.  <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_automatic"/> discusses how to automatically schedule upgrades as they are made available.
    </para>

    <!-- ========================================================= -->
    <sect2 id="upgrade_manager_manual">
      <title>Manual Upgrade</title>
      <para>
        If the &eg; is not configured to receive and install updates automatically (see <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_automatic"/>), this tab displays available upgrades.  The Manual Upgrade tab is seen in <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_manual_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="upgrade_manager_manual_figure">
        <title>Manual Upgrade Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/upgrademngr/upgrade_manual.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>  
      </figure>
      <para>
        When available, upgrades are displayed and may be selected for installation.
      </para>     
    </sect2>
  
    <!-- ========================================================= -->
    <sect2 id="upgrade_manager_automatic">
      <title>Schedule Automatic Upgrade</title>
      <para>
        The Schedule Automatic Upgrade tab, as shown in <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_automatic_figure"/>, is used to configure the &eg; to contact Metavize periodically to check for upgrades.  It can optionaly be configured to install upgrades without Administrative intervention.
      </para>
      <figure id="upgrade_manager_automatic_figure">
        <title>Schedule Automatic Upgrade Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/upgrademngr/upgrade_automatic.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Schedule Automatic Upgrade tab is divided into two sections.  The left section is used to confiure the times when &eg; checks for updates.  In the right panel, Administrators can configure the behavior once &eg; discovers updates.  If <guilabel>Do not automatically install new upgrades</guilabel> is selected then &eg; will only register that updates are available, ane make then visible on the Manual Upgrade Tab.  Installation must be done manually (see <xref linkend="upgrade_manager_manual"/>.
      </para>
      <para>
        If <guilabel>Automatically install new upgrades</guilabel> is selected, then &eg; will install upgrades as they are released/made available from Metavize.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>


  <!-- ############################################################# -->
  <sect1 id="upgrade_manager_qa">
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaset>  
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>Which should I use - manual or automatic upgrades?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            It all depends on your preference.  For example, some organizations configure desktop Virus Scanning software to automatically update, while others prefer to perform this manually.  
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
    </qandaset>
  </sect1>    

</chapter>
