<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="spyware_tran">
  <title>Spyware Blocker</title>
  <para>
    The Spyware Blocker Appliance is identified by the
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="figure/spyware/spyware_tran_icon.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
    symbol.  If the Spyware Blocker Appliance is not installed, please refer to <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances"/> for installation instructions.
  </para>

  <para>
    Spyware Blocker examines web requests from your protected network.  As web resources are accessed, they are compared against several lists for suspicion of being <glossterm linkend="gloss_spyware">spyware</glossterm>.  Spyware Blocker looks for <glossterm linkend="gloss_cookie">cookies</glossterm> from known spyware sites, <glossterm linkend="gloss_url">URLs</glossterm> of known offenders, and <glossterm linkend="gloss_activex">ActiveX Controls</glossterm> known to be spyware applications.  Spyware Blocker also examines the <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP Address</glossterm> of the site being visited, and compares it against a list of offending <glossterm linkend="gloss_subnet">subnets</glossterm>.
  </para>

  <para>
    In the unusual event that a web site legitimately visited by members of your organization is found in one of the Spyware Blocker Appliance's lists, administrators are able to create exception rules.
  </para>

  <sect1 id="spyware_tran_adminui">
    <title>Administrative Interface</title>
    <para>
      The interface for the Spyware Blocker is presented as four tabs.  The first two, <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_block"/> and <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_passlist"/> provide the administrator the ability to view/change sites which will or will not be considered spyware.  The <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_generalsettings"/> tab provides access to properties not directly related to spyware lists.   The last tab, <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_eventlog"/>, allows administrators to view events (see <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances_eventlog"/>).
    </para>
    <!-- ========================================= -->
    <sect2 id="spyware_tran_adminui_block">
      <title>Block List</title>
      <para>
        The block list tab presents administrators the ability to modify the four major categories of spyware blocking.  Refer to the section for each sub-tab for more detail.
        <tip>
          <para>
            If you wish to prevent a site from being categorized as <glossterm linkend="gloss_spyware">spyware</glossterm>, it is recommended you <emphasis>not</emphasis> attempt to remove that site's data from one of the Block Lists.  Instead, refer to <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_passlist"/> on how to create exclusions to the blocking rules.
          </para>
        </tip>        
      </para>

      <!-- ========================================= -->
      <sect3 id="spyware_tran_adminui_block_cookie">
        <title>Cookie List</title>
        <para>
          The <glossterm linkend="gloss_cookie">Cookie</glossterm> List is a collection of <glossterm linkend="gloss_hostname">Hostnames</glossterm>.  Should someone within the protected network visit one of these sites and that site attempt to set a cookie, &eg; will prevent the cookie from being set.  The interface for viewing and manipulating the cookie list can be seen in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_block_cookie_figure"/>
        </para>
        <figure id="spyware_tran_adminui_block_cookie_figure">
          <title>Cookie List Tab</title>
            <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/spyware/spyware_block_cookie.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          As seen in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_block_cookie_figure"/>, the Cookie List is presented as a table.  The column labeled <guilabel>identification</guilabel> contains the address of the offending site.  The next column, <guilabel>block</guilabel>, is used to enable/disable blocking of cookies from that site.  Note that when creating a new entry, the value for <guilabel>identification</guilabel> can either be a <link linkend="appendix_syntax_simpleipaddr">Simple IP Address</link> or hostname.
        </para>
        <tip>
          <para>
            If you wish to prevent a site from being categorized as <glossterm linkend="gloss_spyware">spyware</glossterm>, it is recommended you <emphasis>not</emphasis> attempt to locate that site in the cookie list and remove the entry.  Instead, refer to <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_passlist"/> on how to create exclusions to the blocking rules.
          </para>
        </tip>        
      </sect3>
      <!-- ========================================= -->
      <sect3 id="spyware_tran_adminui_block_subnet">
        <title>Subnet List</title>
        <!--
          WRS: I am having trouble justifying this feature.
        -->
        <para>
          The <glossterm linkend="gloss_subnet">Subnet</glossterm> List is a collection of subnets.  When &eg; observes a connection from within the protected network, log entries can be made.  This alerts Administrators of questionable traffic they may wish to block via other mechanisms (such as Firewall, as discussed in <xref linkend="firewall_tran"/>).  The interface for the Subnet list is shown in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_block_subnet_figure"/>.
        </para>
        <figure id="spyware_tran_adminui_block_subnet_figure">
          <title>Subnet List Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/spyware/spyware_block_subnet.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          The Subnet list comes pre-populated with known spyware, categorized by their content type.  Administrators can turn on/off the tracking of subnets by checking/unchecking the <guilabel>log</guilabel> field.
        </para>
        <para>
          Optionally, Administrators can add their own entries by pushing the add (plus) button to the left.  When creating a new entry, the value for <guilabel>identification</guilabel> can either be in <link linkend="appendix_syntax_simpleipaddr">Simple IP Address</link> or <link linkend="appendix_syntax_networknetmask">Network/Netmask</link> format.  The <guilabel>name</guilabel> and <guilabel>description</guilabel> fields are simply for Administrator reference.
        </para>
      </sect3>
  
      <!-- ========================================= -->
      <sect3 id="spyware_tran_adminui_block_activex">
        <title>ActiveX List</title>
        <para>
          The <glossterm linkend="gloss_activex">ActiveX</glossterm> List is a collection of ActiveX Control identifiers.  When a page is fetched from a machine within the protected network with one of the listed ActiveX controls, that control is blocked.  The complete interface for the ActiveX list is shown in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_block_activex_figure"/>.
        </para>
        <figure id="spyware_tran_adminui_block_activex_figure">
          <title>ActiveX List Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/spyware/spyware_block_activex.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          As seen in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_block_activex_figure"/>, the ActiveX List is presented as a table.  The column labeled <guilabel>identification</guilabel> contains the <quote>Object ID</quote> of the offending control.  The next column, <guilabel>block</guilabel>, is used to enable/disable blocking of controls with that Object ID.
        </para>
      </sect3>
  
      <!-- ========================================= -->
      <sect3 id="spyware_tran_adminui_block_urllist">
        <title>URL List</title>
        <para>
          The <glossterm linkend="gloss_url">URL</glossterm> List, as shown in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_block_urllist_figure"/>, is used to enable the blocking of web traffic to sites known to be hosting <glossterm linkend="gloss_spyware">spyware</glossterm> or advertisements.
        </para>
        
        <figure id="spyware_tran_adminui_block_urllist_figure">
          <title>URL List Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/spyware/spyware_block_urllist.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          To enable blocking of these sites, select <guilabel>Enable</guilabel>.
        </para>
      </sect3>            
    </sect2>
  
    <!-- ========================================= -->
    <sect2 id="spyware_tran_adminui_passlist">
      <title>Pass List</title>
      <para>
        The Pass List is used by administrators to declare those sites which should not be blocked as spyware.  It is used when someone within the protected network needs to visit a site which is listed on one of the Block Lists.  The complete interface for the Pass List is shown in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_passlist_figure"/>
      </para>
      <figure id="spyware_tran_adminui_passlist_figure">
        <title>Pass List Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/spyware/spyware_passlist.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        As seen in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_passlist_figure"/>, the Pass List is presented as a table of domains.  To add a new entry, push the add (plus) bottom to the left of the table.  The <guilabel>domain</guilabel> field is the only required field.  The format of the <guilabel>domain</guilabel> is <constant>http://<replaceable>approved_domain</replaceable></constant> where <replaceable>approved_domain</replaceable> is replaced with the approved domain.
        <tip>
          <para>
            Although it may seem as one could enter a full URL path into the <guilabel>domain</guilabel> field, <guilabel>domain</guilabel> only handles top-level domains.  For example, attempting to place <constant>http://some_domain.com/site1</constant> into the Pass List will cause all paths at <constant>http://some_domain.com</constant> to be passed (such as <constant>http://some_domain.com/site2</constant>).
          </para>
        </tip>
        Administrators can enable/disable a given domain from being bypassed by checking the <guilabel>pass</guilabel> field.
      </para>
    </sect2>
    
  
    <!-- ========================================= -->
    <sect2 id="spyware_tran_adminui_generalsettings">
      <title>General Settings</title>
      <para>
        The General Settings tab for the Spyware Blocker Appliance is shown in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_generalsettings_figure"/>
      </para>
      <figure id="spyware_tran_adminui_generalsettings_figure">
        <title>General Settings Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/spyware/spyware_general.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        There is only one setting on this tab, which allows administrators to disable all ActiveX controls.  Setting this value by checking the box causes &eg; to block all ActiveX controls from being delivered to machines on the protected network.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  
  
    <!-- ========================================= -->
    <sect2 id="spyware_tran_adminui_eventlog">
      <title>Event Log</title>
      <para>
        The Events tab contents is shown in <xref linkend="spyware_tran_adminui_eventlog_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="spyware_tran_adminui_eventlog_figure">
        <title>Event Log</title>
  
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/spyware/spyware_eventlog.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Events Tab is another implementation of an Event Log, as described in <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances_eventlog"/>.  The complete list of columns and their meaning is as follows.
        <variablelist>
          <title>Events Tab</title>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>timestamp</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The time the event took place
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>action</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action which took place (e.g. <constant>block</constant>).
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>client</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The client <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of the traffic.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>request</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                A description of the request made (e.g. <constant>http://someurl/somepath.html</constant>).
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>          
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>reason for action</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The reason the action was taken (e.g. <constant>in URL list</constant>).
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>direction</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The direction (<constant>inbound</constant> or <constant>outbound</constant>) of the traffic.  Note that <constant>inbound</constant> means into the protected network.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>server</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The server <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of the traffic.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>                                                                
        </variablelist>
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="spyware_tran_qa">
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaset>

      &spyware_tran_qa;
    
    </qandaset>
  </sect1>

</chapter>

