  

  <!-- ========================================================= -->  
  <sect1 id="gblcfg_tab_networking">
    <title>Networking</title>
    <para>
      The Networking panel controls commonn properties related to the &eg;'s presence on its various network interfaces.
    </para>

    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddrs">
      <title>External Addresses</title>
      <para>
        The External Addresses Tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddrs_figure"/>, lets administrators control how their &eg; appears to the outside (non-protected) network.
      </para>
      <figure id="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddrs_figure">
        <title>External Addresses Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddrs.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The &eg; can be set-up to either have a <glossterm linkend="gloss_static_ip">static</glossterm> or dynamic IP address.  For a static IP, administrators must configure the network settings as they would for any system on the network.  Dynamic addresses are obtained from <glossterm linkend="gloss_dhcp">DHCP</glossterm>.
      </para>
      <para>
        The interface for configuring these external settings is divided into three sections.  The first section determines if the &eg; is using a static or dynamic address.  To choose between these options, the administrator selects either <guilabel>Automatically Set</guilabel> or <guilabel>Manually Set</guilabel>.  If <guilabel>Automatically Set</guilabel> is selected, the &eg; will use DHCP to obtain network settings and display them in the boxes below.  If <guilabel>Manually Set</guilabel> is selected, the administrator must manually set the <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP Address</glossterm>, <glossterm linkend="gloss_netmask">Netmask</glossterm>, <glossterm linkend="gloss_default_route">Default Route</glossterm> (sometimes referred to as <quote>gateway</quote>), as well as a primary <glossterm linkend="gloss_dns">DNS</glossterm> server and a secondary DNS server (optional).
      </para>
      <para>
        Should <guilabel>Automatically Set</guilabel> be selected, then administrators can optionally request a renewal of their <glossterm linkend="gloss_dhcp_lease">DHCP Lease</glossterm> via the <guilabel>Renew DHCP Lease</guilabel> button.  This is the second section as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddrs_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <para>
        Whether <guilabel>Automatically Set</guilabel> or <guilabel>Manually Set</guilabel> is selected for the external interface, the <guilabel>Run Connectivity Test</guilabel> button can be used to perform a test of these settings.  This is the third section as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddrs_figure"/>.  Activating the test will then report its findings (success/failure).
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddraliases">
      <title>External Address Aliasess</title>
      <para>
        The External Address Aliases tab, as seen in, <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddraliases_figure"/>, is for complex &eg; deployments.
      </para>
      <figure id="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddraliases_figure">
        <title>External Address Aliases Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddraliases.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        Use of this feature depends on if the &eg; is providing <glossterm linkend="gloss_nat">NAT</glossterm> services to the internal (protected) network.  If running NAT (see <xref linkend="nat_tran"/>), then this feature can be used to receive traffic for more than just the network of the &eg;'s external interface.
      </para>
      <para>
        If your &eg; is not running NAT (sometimes called <quote>bridge</quote> mode), then each addition to the External Address Aliases will allow &eg; to route traffic for networks other than that defined by its external IP address.
      </para>
    </sect2>  


    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="gblcfg_tab_networking_hostname">
      <title>Hostname</title>
      <para>
        The Hostname Tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking_hostname_figure"/>, configures how the &eg; may be addresses other than by <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm>.
      </para>
      <figure id="gblcfg_tab_networking_hostname_figure">
        <title>Hostname Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_networking_hostname.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Hostname tab is divided into two sections, <guilabel>Hostname</guilabel> and <guilabel>Dynamic DNS</guilabel>.  The <guilabel>Hostname</guilabel> section lets the Administrator define the hostname of the <glossterm linkend="gloss_hostname">hostname</glossterm> of the &eg;.  The optional <guilabel>Hostname resolves publicly</guilabel> instructs the &eg; that users on the Internet can use this hostname when connecting to the machine.  This is useful when using features such as VPN (see <xref linkend="openvpn_tran"/>) or Quarantine Digests (see <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_email_quarantine"/>) which must embed URLs to contact the machine.  When <guilabel>Hostname resolves publicly</guilabel> is checked, such URL will use the hostname rather than IP address of the &eg;.
        <note>
          <para>
            Note that the hostname entered in this screen is used for generation of the digital certificate for the &eg; (see <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs"/>).
          </para>
        </note>        
      </para>
        
      <para>
        The <guilabel>Dynamic DNS</guilabel> tab lets Administrators leverage one of several <glossterm linkend="gloss_dyndns">dynamic DNS</glossterm> providers such that the hostname of their &eg; will be accessible from the internet.
      </para>
    </sect2>     
    
  </sect1> 

