  <!-- ========================================================= -->  
  <sect1 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin">
    <title>Remote Admin</title>
    <para>
      The Remote Admin tab provides control over the process and rules for administering the &eg;.  It is divided into 5 sub tabs.  The first, as discussed in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_accounts"/>, is used to create accounts which can administer the &eg;.  The next section, covered in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access"/>, is used to control access to the Administrative Console from a network level.  The third tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs"/>, is used to control the Digital Certificate used when accessing the &eg; via Secure Sockets Layer (<glossterm linkend="gloss_ssl">SSL</glossterm>).  The fourth tab, discussed in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring"/>, is used to configure industry standard monitoring protocols such as <glossterm linkend="gloss_snmp">SNMP</glossterm> and <glossterm linkend="gloss_syslog">Syslog</glossterm>.  The final tab allows administrators to reboot their &eg;, as discussed in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_reboot"/>.
    </para>

    <!-- ========================================================= -->  
    <sect2 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_accounts">
      <title>Admin Accounts</title>
      <para>
        The Admin Accounts Tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_accounts_figure"/>, is used to add/modify administrator accounts.  Administrators are users who are able to use the Administrative Console.  This is not to be confused with end-users (people who browse the web, receive email, etc) who do not need logins to the &eg;.
      </para>
  
      <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_accounts_figure">
        <title>Admin Accounts Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_accounts.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        There are three actions one would take with the Admin Accounts Tab: adding an administrator, removing an administrator, or changing an administrator's password.  Each of these actions are detailed as follows.  Note that one or more of these action may be taken, but do not take effect into the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button is pushed.
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <title>Common Administrative Actions</title>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Adding an Account</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              To add an account, push the add (plus) button to the left of the panel.  This adds a new (blank) row to the table.  The <guilabel>name</guilabel> column is a descriptive name, such as <quote>Emma Scott</quote> or <quote>Jun Wang</quote>.  The <guilabel>login</guilabel> column is a login name, such as <quote>escott</quote> or <quote>jwang</quote>.  
            </para>
            <para>
              The next two columns, <guilabel>set new password</guilabel> and <guilabel>confirm new password</guilabel>, should be populated with the new Administrator's password.  Both fields need to be filled with the same password.  The next field is <guilabel>original user's password</guilabel>.  When adding a new user, <emphasis>this field is automatically populated.  Do not change the default value.</emphasis>  The past field is for the new Administrator's email address.  It may be left blank.
            </para>
            <para>
              The new account will become active once the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button is pushed.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Removing an Administrator</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              To remove an administrator account, highlight the account (row) to be deleted then push the remove (minus) button to the left.  You must then enter the account about to be deleted's password in the <guilabel>original user's password</guilabel>.  The account will be removed once the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button is pushed.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Changing a Password</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              To change the password for an administrative account, highlight the account (row) of the account to change.  Then enter the new password into the <guilabel>set new password</guilabel> and <guilabel>confirm new password</guilabel> fields.  The existing (current) password must then be entered into the <guilabel>original user's password</guilabel> field.
            </para>
            <para>
              The password change will take effect once the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button is pushed.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>    
      </variablelist>
      
    </sect2>


    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access">
      <title>Access</title>
      <para>
        The Access Tab controls how Administrators may use the Administrative Console to view and change the &eg;.
      </para>

      <!-- ........................................................ -->
      <sect3 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access_restrictions">
        <title>Restrictions</title>
        <para>
          The Restrictions tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access_restrictions_figure"/>, lets Administrators control how the Administrative Interface can be used.
        </para>
        <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access_restrictions_figure">
          <title>Restrictions Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access_restrictions.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          <emphasis>External</emphasis> administration is defined as someone accessing the Administrative Interface from outside the protected network.  <emphasis>Internal</emphasis> administration is someone accessing the Administrative Interface from within the protected network.  Someone from the <glossterm linkend="gloss_dmz">DMZ</glossterm> is considered <emphasis>external</emphasis>.
          <note>
            <para>
              The current external IP address can be found from the <link linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking_extaddrs">Network Settings</link> panel.  If the &eg; is running <glossterm linkend="gloss_nat">NAT</glossterm>, the internal IP can be found from the NAT settings as explained in <xref linkend="nat_tran"/>.  If the system is not running NAT, then the internal IP is the same as the external IP.
            </para>
          </note>
          We will now discuss the details of configuring the &eg; for external and internal administration.
        </para>
        <simplesect>
          <title><guilabel>External Remote Administration</guilabel></title>
          <para>
            External administration can be enabled/disabled by selecting either the <guilabel>Allow</guilabel> or <guilabel>Deny</guilabel> options within the External Remote Administration section.  Note that if enabled, <emphasis>all administration traffic is passed over a secure (SSL) connection</emphasis>.
          </para>
          <para>
            If administration from outside the protected network is enabled, Administrators can also choose to restrict administration from a select set of machines.  This restriction is set by first selecting <guilabel>Restrict</guilabel> then populating the <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr"><guilabel>IP Address</guilabel></glossterm> and <glossterm linkend="gloss_netmask"><guilabel>Netmask</guilabel></glossterm> fields.
          </para>
        </simplesect>
        <simplesect>
          <title><guilabel>Internal Remote Administration</guilabel></title>
          <para>
            Internal administration can be configured to require an encrypted (SSL) connection or not.  To require an SSL connection, select the <guilabel>Disallow</guilabel> option under <guilabel>Internal Remote Administration</guilabel>.  Note that secure remote administration is <emphasis>always</emphasis> enabled from the internal network.
          </para>
        </simplesect>
      </sect3>


      <!-- ........................................................ -->
      <sect3 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access_pubaddr">
        <title>Public Address</title>
        <para>
          The Public Address Tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access_pubaddr_figure"/>, should only be used under special circumstances.  Those circumstances involve a different address used for access from the Internet vs. the address of the external interface of the &eg;.
        </para>
        <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access_pubaddr_figure">
          <title>Public Address Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_access_pubaddr.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          Although redundant, an &eg; can be deployed behind a router or other network device which performs redirection.  For example, such a device may redirect all traffic on its IP address for port 443 to the &eg; on port 8443.
        </para>
        <para>
          In such a scenario, the address of the &eg; is not the address used by people on the general Internet.  From outside the corporate network, an Administrator could not reach the &eg;.  To address this situation, the Public Address tab should be used.  Enter the IP address and port which will be used for Internet access to the &eg;.
          <note>
            <para>
              The port which is required for external access is 443.  It is permissible to use a value other than 443 as the value for <guilabel>port</guilabel> on the &eg;, but the device performing redirection should honor 443 as the external mapping.
            </para>
          </note>
        </para>
      </sect3>      
      
    </sect2>

    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs">
      <title>Certificates</title>
      <para>
        The Certificates Tab controls the <glossterm linkend="gloss_digitalcert">Digital Certificate</glossterm> (<quote>cert</quote>) used by the &eg; when using <glossterm linkend="gloss_ssl">SSL</glossterm>.  Without a properly installed and signed cert, users who browse to the &eg; will receive warning messages from their browser.  Note that the Administrative Console, as well as the Quarantine features use SSL for user interaction.
      </para>
      <bridgehead renderas="sect3">Background on Certificates</bridgehead>
      <para>
        Although a complete discussion of Digital Certificates is beyond the scope of this document, some background and terminology are warranted.  Digital Certificates are used by a web server to identify itself.  For example, if you visit Amazon.com to purchase a book you are using SSL when you enter your credit card number.  Two things take place as you perform this transaction.  First, SSL encrypts your web session to prevent any malicious parties from intercepting your personal information.  Secondly, your browser requested Amazon.com's Digital Certificate to make sure you were in fact visiting <quote>amazon.com</quote>.
      </para>
      <para>
        This second step is called server authentication.  Your browser knows that you typed <quote>www.amazon.com</quote>, and expects the web server to return a certificate which declares <quote>this is 'www.amazon.com'</quote>.  Since a Digital Certificate is easy to create (you could use the &eg; Administrative Console to create a certificate for <quote>www.amazon.com</quote>), your browser must also make sure the certificate is authentic.  This is done by examining the <emphasis>signature</emphasis> on the certificate against a list of known <quote>certificate authorities</quote>.
      </para>
      <para>
        All browsers come with a list of dozens of certificate authorities, along with information to validate when those authorities sign web server certificates.  In our example with Amazon.com, the digital certificate for <quote>www.amazon.com</quote> is signed by a Certificate Authority named <quote>Verisign</quote>.  When Amazon presented its certificate to your browser, your browser went through the following steps:
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Visited a web site with the address <quote>www.amazon.com</quote> and requested its digital certificate.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Examined the returned certificate and found that it claimed to be for a site called <quote>www.amazon.com</quote>.  If the address you entered into your browser did not match the name of the certificate, the browser would have issued a warning that the name of the certificate does not match the visited site.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Found that this certificate was signed by an authority called <quote>Verisign</quote>.  The browser then went through its list of pre installed Certificate Authorities and found and entry for Verisign.  Otherwise, the browser would have issued a warning that the certificate was signed by an unknown authority.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Verified the signature on Amazon's certificate was in fact the signature of Verisign.  Otherwise, the browser would have issued a warning that the signature was invalid.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          
        </orderedlist>
      </para>
      <para>
        Unlike the steps listed above with Amazon, a new &eg; installation will cause the browser to issue warnings.  This is due to the fact that the Digital Certificate used by the &eg; is not signed by a known Certificate Authority.  The initial (default) certificate is in fact a <emphasis>self-signed</emphasis> certificate (which is equivalent to <quote>not signed by anyone known to the browser</quote>).
      </para>

      <bridgehead renderas="sect3">Obtaining a Digital Certificate</bridgehead>
      <para>
        To prevent browser warnings, two things are required.  First is that the name of the &eg; must be known to the Internet.  This is called the hostname of the machine, configuration of which is discussed in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking"/>.
      </para>
      <para>
        The second required step is to obtain a cert from a well-known certificate authority.  There are many certificate authorities which charge varying fees for a digital certificate.  Examples of popular certificate authorities include <ulink url="http://www.verisign.com">Verisign</ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.thwate.com"> Thwate</ulink>.
      </para>
      <para>
        To obtain a valid, signed certificate from a certificate authority, the following steps must be followed.
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              A self-signed certificate must be created (see <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_selfsigned"/>).  This certificate includes not only the name of the &eg; machine, but information about the owning organization (name, location, etc).  The initial self-signed certificate created by a new &eg; deployment lacks much of this information.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              A Certificate Signature Request (CSR) must be created (see <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_csr"/>).  This is a standard digital document accepted by all certificate authorities as the initial step in the process of obtaining a digital certificate.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The CSR must be presented to a certificate authority along with any payments for the signature service.  The certificate authority may also request additional information to verify that you <quote>own</quote> the web site for-which you are requesting the certificate.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              After performing verifications, the certificate authority returns a signed digital certificate for your &eg;.  This certificate can then be installed (<quote>imported</quote>) into the &eg;, as discussed in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_import"/>.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </para>

      <!-- ........................................................ -->
      <sect3 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_status">
        <title>Status</title>
        <para>
          The Status Tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_status_figure"/>, displays information about the currently installed <glossterm linkend="gloss_digitalcert">Digital Certificate</glossterm>.
        </para>
        <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_status_figure">
          <title>Status Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_status.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          The status screen displays information such as the lifetime and Distinguished Name (<quote>DN</quote>) of the certificate.  Note that the initial certificate for a &eg; lacks much information (and should be replaced, as discussed in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation"/>).
        </para>
      </sect3>

      <!-- ........................................................ -->
      <sect3 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation">
        <title>Generation</title>
        <para>
          The Generation Tab contains buttons to follow the required steps to obtain a working digital certificate for an &eg;: creating a self-signed certificate, generating a certificate signature request, and importing the signed certificate into the &eg;.
        </para>

        <!-- ........................................................ -->
        <sect4 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_selfsigned">
          <title>Generate Self Signed Certificate</title>
          <para>
            The Generate Self Signed Certificate Window, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_selfsigned_figure"/>, is used by Administrators to generate a new self-signed digital certificate..
          </para>
          <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_selfsigned_figure">
            <title>Generate Self Signed Certificate Window</title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_selfsigned.png" />
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
          <para>
            All information on this form must be filled-in, except the <guilabel>Hostname</guilabel> which is automatically obtained from the hostname of the &eg; (see <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_networking_hostname"/>).
          </para> 
        </sect4>


        <!-- ........................................................ -->
        <sect4 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_csr">
          <title>Generate Certificate Signature Request</title>
          <para>
            The Generate Certificate Signature Request (CSR) Window, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_csr_figure"/>, will produce a CSR based on the current certificate information (see <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_selfsigned"/>);
          </para>
          <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_csr_figure">
            <title>Generate Certificate Signature Request Window</title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_csr.png" />
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
          <para>
            To use, push the <guilabel>proceed</guilabel> button as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_csr_figure"/>.  This will fill-in the window with several lines of text starting with <constant>-----BEGIN NEW CERTIFICATE REQUEST-----</constant>.  You should cut and paste this text into the form provided by your certificate authority.
            <tip>
              <para>
                Many certificate authorities offer different types of certificates.  For the &eg;, an "SSL" or "Web Server" certificate should be purchased.
              </para>
            </tip>
          </para>
        </sect4>


        <!-- ........................................................ -->
        <sect4 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_import">
          <title>Import Signed Certificate</title>
          <para>
            The Import Signed Certificate Window, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_import_figure"/> is used to enter the signed certificate returned from the certificate authority.
          </para>
          <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_import_figure">
            <title>Import Signed Certificate Window</title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_import.png" />
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
          <para>
            The certificate itself will either be emailed or received in a web browser.  Like the process of creating the CSR, importing the certificate requires one to cut-and-paste text into a window (as shown in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_import_figure"/>).
          </para>
          <para>
            Some CAs may also return a second <quote>intermediate</quote> certificate.  If your CA has provided such a certificate, it may be pasted into the bottom window as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_certs_generation_import_figure"/>.
            <note>
              <para>
                If there is no intermediate certificate provided by your CA, this field may be left blank.
              </para>
            </note>
          </para>
        </sect4>                 
        
      </sect3>
      
    </sect2>

    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring">
      <title>Monitoring</title>
      <para>
        The Monitoring Tab lets the Administrator configure <glossterm linkend="gloss_snmp">SNMP</glossterm> (see <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_snmp"/> as well as <glossterm linkend="gloss_syslog">Syslog</glossterm> (as discussed in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_syslog"/>) support.
      </para>

      <!-- ........................................................ -->
      <sect3 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_snmp">
        <title>SNMP Monitoring</title>
        <para>
          The <glossterm linkend="gloss_snmp">SNMP</glossterm> Monitoring tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_snmp_figure"/>, controls how the &eg; uses SNMP.
        </para>
        <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_snmp_figure">
          <title>SNMP Monitoring Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_snmp.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          The &eg; is able to respond to read-only SNMP queries.  It exports MIB-II (see RFC 1213), as well as (optionally) sends <glossterm linkend="gloss_trap">traps</glossterm>.  To enable the &eg; to field SNMP queries, select the <guilabel>Enable SNMP Monitoring</guilabel> option as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_snmp_figure"/>.
        </para>
        <para>
          If <guilabel>Enable SNMP Monitoring</guilabel> is selected, three additional pieces of information should be provided.  The first is the <guilabel>Community</guilabel>, which is used in SNMP v1 to authenticate queries.
          <warning>
            <para>
              Be sure to change the default community value when enabling this feature
            </para>
          </warning>
          The next two fields are <guilabel>System Contact</guilabel> and <guilabel>System Location</guilabel>.  Although not required for normal operation, they greatly assist in troubleshooting.  They should be populated with contact information and the physical location of the &eg; (respectively).
        </para>
        <para>
          The &eg; can also be configured to send warm and cold start traps.  To enable the sending of traps, select <guilabel>Enable Traps</guilabel> at the bottom of the SNMP Monitoring tab.  You must then provide a host/port (via the <guilabel>Host</guilabel> and <guilabel>Port</guilabel> respectively).  The field <guilabel>Community</guilabel> must be populated with the community string for the trap-receiving server.
          <note>
            <para>
              Not all SNMP trap receiver tools require a community string.  If your tool does not require a community string, the <guilabel>Community</guilabel> field can be left blank.
            </para>
          </note>
        </para>
      </sect3>


      <!-- ........................................................ -->
      <sect3 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_syslog">
        <title>Syslog Monitoring</title>
        <para>
          Syslog Monitoring, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_syslog_figure"/>, allows Administrators to redirect information from the &eg; to a <glossterm linkend="gloss_syslog">Syslog</glossterm> server.
        </para>
        <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_syslog_figure">
          <title>Syslog Monitoring Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_monitoring_syslog.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
  
        <para>
          From the Syslog Monitoring tab, Administrators can enable/disable their &eg; from sending Syslog messages via selecting either <guilabel>Disable Syslog Monitoring</guilabel> or <guilabel>Enable Syslog Monitoring</guilabel>.  If <guilabel>Enable Syslog Monitoring</guilabel> is selected, further information is required for this feature to function.
        </para>
        <para>
          The <guilabel>Host</guilabel> field is the name of the server running a Syslog server.  This server should be configured to allow remote submission of Syslog messages.  The next field is <guilabel>Port</guilabel>, and should only be changed from the standard port (512) should the Syslog server be listening on a non-standard port.
        </para>
        <para>
          <guilabel>Facility</guilabel> is the Syslog facility for which the &eg; messages will be submitted.  The <guilabel>Facility</guilabel> contains all standard Syslog values for <constant>facility</constant>.  <guilabel>Threshold</guilabel> is the minimum Syslog threshold, such that &eg; will not send messages below this level.  Note that &eg; sends messages at the <constant>informational</constant>, <constant>notice</constant> and <constant>warning</constant> levels.  In general, messages indicating traffic was inspected and found not to contain questionable content is sent as <constant>informational</constant>.  Inspected traffic which required &eg; to take action (for example, blocking a restricted web page) is sent as <constant>notice</constant>.  The exception to this last case is for viruses found, which are sent as <constant>warning</constant> messages.
        </para>
        
      </sect3> 
      
    </sect2>

    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_reboot">
      <title>Manual Reboot</title>
      <para>
        The Manual Reboot Tab, as seen in <xref linkend="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_reboot_figure"/>, provides the ability for Administrators to reboot their &eg; system without physical access to the machine.
      </para>
      <figure id="gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_reboot_figure">
        <title>Manual Reboot Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/gblcfg/gblcfg_tab_remoteadmin_reboot.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        To reboot, push the <guilabel>Reboot EdgeGuard</guilabel> button.
      </para>
    </sect2> 
        
  </sect1>
