<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="ids_tran">

  <title>Intrusion Prevention</title>
  <para>
    The Intrusion Prevention Appliance is identified by the
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="figure/ids/ids_tran_icon.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
    symbol.  If the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is not installed, please refer to <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances"/> for installation instructions.
  </para>
  <para>
    As its name implies, the Intrusion Prevention Appliance prevents known malicious exploits from entering your protected network.  It is based on technology from <ulink  url="http://www.snort.org/">Snort.org</ulink>.  The Snort community maintains information about known exploits, and produces lists of <emphasis>signatures</emphasis> from this information.  The Intrusion Prevention Appliance uses rules created from these lists and applies the rules against the traffic entering your network to protect your network.
  </para>
  <para>
    Note that except for <xref linkend="ids_tran_eventlog"/>, the configuration of the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is an advanced topic.
  </para>

  <sect1 id="ids_tran_adminui">
    <title>Administrative Interface</title>

    <para>
      The Intrusion Prevention Appliance interface has three tabs.  The first two tabs, discussed in <xref linkend="ids_tran_rule"/> and <xref linkend="ids_tran_varlist"/>, allow the administrator to configure <emphasis>advanced</emphasis> settings.  The last tab, <xref linkend="ids_tran_eventlog"/>, allows the administrator to view intrusion scanning events (see <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances_eventlog"/>).
    </para>
  

    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="ids_tran_rule">
      <title>Rule List</title>
      <para>
        The interface for the Rule List tab of the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is shown in <xref linkend="ids_tran_rule_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="ids_tran_rule_figure">
        <title>Rule List Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/ids/ids_rulelist.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        As stated previously, the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is based on technology from <ulink  url="http://www.snort.org/">Snort.org</ulink>.  <emphasis>Adding or modifying rules in the syntax defined by Snort.org is an advanced topic,</emphasis> that will not be covered in this manual.
      </para>
      <para>
        In most cases, an Administrator should only need to alter the <guilabel>block</guilabel> and/or <guilabel>log</guilabel> values of a given rule.  Checking the <guilabel>block</guilabel> field of a rule causes the Intrusion Prevention Appliance to enable the rule and block traffic that matches the rule signature.  Checking the <guilabel>log</guilabel> field of a rule causes the Intrusion Prevention Appliance to log traffic that matches the rule signature.
        <tip>
          <para>
            The Intrusion Prevention Appliance ships with a default set of rules that have been configured to block malicious exploits.  You should only need to disable a rule if that rule blocks traffic from a unique software application that you must use.
          </para>
        </tip> 
      </para>
    </sect2>


    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="ids_tran_varlist">
      <title>Variable List</title>
      <para>
        The interface for the Variable List tab of the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is shown in <xref linkend="ids_tran_varlist_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="ids_tran_varlist_figure">
        <title>Variable List Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/ids/ids_varlist.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        As stated previously, the Intrusion Prevention Appliance is based on technology from <ulink  url="http://www.snort.org/">Snort.org</ulink>.  <emphasis>Adding or modifying variables is a advanced topic</emphasis> that will not be covered in this manual.
      </para>
    </sect2>
    

    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="ids_tran_eventlog">
      <title>Event Log</title>
      <para>
        The Events Log tab is shown in <xref linkend="ids_tran_eventlog_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="ids_tran_eventlog_figure">
        <title>Event Log Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/ids/ids_eventlog.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Events tab is another implementation of an Event Log, as described in <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances_eventlog"/>.  The complete list of columns and their meaning is as follows.
        <variablelist>
          <title>Events Tab</title>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>timestamp</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The time the event took place
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>action</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action that was taken on the traffic. Valid values are <constant>block</constant> and <constant>pass</constant>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>client</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The client <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of the traffic.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>reason for action</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The rule that was applied to the traffic.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>direction</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The direction (<constant>inbound</constant> or <constant>outbound</constant>) of the traffic.  Most Intrusion Prevention Appliance rules only apply to the <constant>inbound</constant> (into the protected network) direction.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>server</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The intended server <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of the traffic.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>                                                                
        </variablelist>        
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="ids_tran_qaXXX">
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaset>  

      &ids_tran_qa;
    
    </qandaset>
  </sect1>  

</chapter>
