<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>

<!-- This file makes part of an XSL Test Suite -->
<!-- Test for complex layout patterns          -->
<!-- Version: 1.1 of 24/08/99                  -->

<manual header="Universal Hammer - Operation Manual">
  <header>
    <title>IDM Universal Hammer</title>
    <subtitle>Operation Manual</subtitle>
    <manufacturer>International Destruction Machines Corp.</manufacturer>
  </header>


  <annotation>
    <p>
      The purpose of this document is to illustrate handling complex 
      layout patterns in the Extended Stylesheet Language (XSL).
      To simulate a real text, I have written an operation instruction
      for a hammer. The genre of operation instructions turned out 
      to be quite convenient for showing most standard formatting 
      properties. Features used in this text include:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li> multi-column text; </li>
      <li> page headers/footers; </li>
      <li> graphics; </li>
      <li> footnotes; </li>
      <li> ordered and unordered lists; </li>
      <li> tables; </li>
      <li> automatically generated table of contents; </li>
      <li> automatically generated analytical index. </li>
    </ul>
  </annotation>
  
  <toc/>   <!-- Table of contents will be generated here -->

  <!-- %%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% -->
  <chapter> 
    <title> Before you start </title>

    <p><b> Dear Customer, </b></p>
    <p> 
      you have just become a proud owner of an IDM universal hammer - the most 
      powerful tool for all kinds of mechanical annihilation. We have made all 
      possible efforts to make this hammer robust and easy to use. To help you 
      manipulate your hammer, we have composed this Operation Manual. Read it 
      through and through several times, until you learn basic principles of 
      hammering exposed herein. 
    </p>
    <p>
      Mechanical tools like hammers often involve serious risk of damaging your
      extremities. If you are new to the art of hammering, it is a good idea 
      to obtain a health insurance policy beforehand; curing fractures may cost.
    </p>

    <disclaimer>
      The manufacturer declines every liability with regard to any direct or 
      consequential damage caused by the equipment to you, your body parts, 
      your personal belongings, your domestic animals e/o beloved relatives. 
      Use this equipment at your own risk, and let God protect your fingers! 
    </disclaimer>

    <p>Have fun with our stuff!</p>

  </chapter>

  <!-- %%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% -->

  <chapter>
    <title> Unpacking &amp; Installing </title>
    <p> 
      The universal hammer comes shipped in a <keyword>carton box</keyword> 
      <figure src="Images/box.jpg" figure-name="Shipping Box."/>.
    </p> 
    <p> 
      To unpack the tool, cut the sealing ribbon on the top of the box, open the box 
      by pulling the two halves of the upper side and turn it upside down. The hammer 
      comes out automatically by gravitation.<footnote>
        When arriving to the ground, the hammer may acquire high velocity. 
        You should protect your <keyword>toes</keyword> with appropriate shoes.
      </footnote>

      To install the hammer, simply hold it by the handle 
      <figure src="Images/hammer.jpg" figure-name="Hammer Parts."/>. 
      Try to perform some oscillatory movements upward and downward. If you 
      feel the hammer is too heavy for you, contact the nearest gym. 
    </p>

  </chapter>

  <!-- %%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% -->

  <chapter>
    <title> Operation </title>
    <subchapter>
      <title> Applications</title>
      <p>
        The universal hammer is a semi-automatic device: when you move it
        upon a target, the tool automatically transfers a good deal of its
        <keyword>momentum</keyword> to the hammered object. The consequences 
        of such a transfer may vary depending on the nature of the target:
      </p>

      <imagelist>
        <li img="Images/nail.jpg"> 
          <keyword>nails</keyword> may either penetrate to their corresponding 
          substrate or bend, depending on your skills;
        </li>
        <li img="Images/screw.jpg"> 
          <keyword>screws</keyword> behave like nails, except that they are 
          less probable to bend but require more momentum to penetrate; 
        </li>
        <li img="Images/brick.jpg"> 
          <keyword>bricks</keyword> normally crack; 
        </li>
        <li img="Images/can.jpg"> 
          <keyword>tins and cans</keyword> deform and flatten; 
        </li>
        <li img="Images/plank.jpg"> 
          <keyword>wood planks</keyword> will probably bounce your hammer 
          back in your face. If you plan to hammer wood planks on a regular 
          basis, protect your face with an appropriate <keyword>metallic grid</keyword>.
        </li>
      </imagelist>
    </subchapter>

    <subchapter>
      <title> How to hammer</title>
      <p>
        To start hammering, first choose the point you want to hit. 
        Then take the handle by your leading hand (either right or left). 
        Raise your hand to an appropriate quota and then
        start moving it downwards. Propelled by the joint effort of the 
        gravity and your muscular strength, the hammer will accelerate 
        quickly. Direct its trajectory in such a way that the target point
        lie within the path of the falling hammer. When the hammer arrives 
        at the specified point, it should have accumulated a good amount
        of <keyword>kinetic energy</keyword>; at the moment of collision, 
        all this energy is released and transferred to the target. 
      </p>
      <p>
        The higher you raise the hammer at the initial phase, the faster
        it will move in the collision point. However, excessive initial 
        elevation can give rise to difficulties in proper pointing of
        the hammer: the faster the tool moves, the more likely you are
        to miss the point. You should learn by  
        experience<footnote>
          While gaining the experience, we strongly recommend to pay maximum 
          attention to safety precautions described in this Instruction. 
        </footnote>
        what is the optimum value of the initial elevation needed in 
        specific cases. 
      </p>
    </subchapter>
  </chapter>  

  <!-- %%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% -->

  <chapter>
    <title> Troubleshooting </title>

    <troubleshooting>

      <problem-cause-remedy> 
        <problem>The hammer is too heavy</problem>
        <cause-remedy>
          <cause>You have chosen a wrong hammer model</cause>
          <remedy>Contact your hammer vendor for a lighter hammer</remedy>
        </cause-remedy>
        <cause-remedy>
          <cause>Your muscles are too weak</cause>
          <remedy>Contact the nearest gym</remedy>
        </cause-remedy>
      </problem-cause-remedy> 
  
      <problem-cause-remedy> 
        <problem>The hammer is too light</problem>
        <cause-remedy>
          <cause>You have chosen a wrong hammer model</cause>
          <remedy>Contact your hammer vendor for a heavier hammer</remedy>
        </cause-remedy>
        <cause-remedy>
          <cause>Your muscles are too strong</cause>
          <remedy>
            You're a <keyword>Schwarzenegger</keyword>. 
            Throw the hammer away, call the Hollywood
          </remedy>
        </cause-remedy>
      </problem-cause-remedy> 
  
      <problem-cause-remedy> 
        <problem>The  hammer handle is broken</problem>
        <cause-remedy>
          <cause>The hammer has been overloaded</cause>
          <remedy>
            Repair the handle and refrain from hammering too hard
          </remedy>
          <remedy>
            Replace the handle
          </remedy>
        </cause-remedy>
        <cause-remedy>
          <cause>The handle was not robust enough</cause>
          <remedy>
            Repair the handle and refrain from hammering too hard
          </remedy>
          <remedy>
            Replace the handle by one made of more robust material 
            (e.g. <keyword>titanium</keyword> alloy)
          </remedy>
        </cause-remedy>
      </problem-cause-remedy> 
 
      <problem-cause-remedy> 
        <problem>You have hurt a <keyword>finger</keyword></problem>
        <cause-remedy>
          <cause>You could not point the hammer well</cause>
          <remedy>
            Try once more. If the problem persists, bandage the finger 
            and call a <keyword>physician</keyword>
          </remedy>
        </cause-remedy>
      </problem-cause-remedy> 
    </troubleshooting>

  </chapter>  

  <!-- %%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% -->

  <chapter>
    <title> Safety Regulations </title>
    <ol>
      <li>
        The hammer is a potential source of danger; its inherent destructive
        power makes it an easy target for misuses. The hammer may be used only 
        for its expressed applications. All other uses are considered dangerous.
        Never permit <keyword>children</keyword> or <keyword>unauthorized persons</keyword> 
        to tamper with the hammer.
      </li>
      <li>
        Store the hammer in a secure place, out of reach of children and pets.
        <b>Never</b> keep it on the upper shelves, to avoid risk of occasional
        fall.
      </li>
      <li>
        After removing all package materials, check the contents to make
        sure that no  damage has occurred during shipping. When in doubt, 
        do not use the hammer and contact the supplier. The packaging 
        materials are a source of pollution and potential hazard if lying 
        around; collect them together and dispose of them properly.
      </li>
    </ol>
  </chapter>  

  <!-- %%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% -->

  <chapter>
    <title> Specifications </title>
    <specifications>

      <item>Type</item>
      <value>IDM UH-1/15</value>

      <item>Weight</item>
      <value>1 lb (453 g)</value>

      <item>Handle</item>
      <value>15 inches (38 cm), made of hickory wood </value>

      <item>Electrical protection</item>
      <value>IP 54</value>

      <item>Compliance</item>
      <value>
        <line>ISO 9001 to 9003</line>
        <line>EEC Directive 456/78 "Hammers"</line>
        <line>ANSI 123-456/89</line>
        <line>DIN 1234567-89</line>
        <line>UNI 10203-92</line>
        <line>GOST 12.345-67</line>
      </value>
    </specifications>

  </chapter>  
  
  <index/> <!-- Index of keywords will be generated here -->
</manual>

