      <!-- ******************************************* -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>Why can't I add/remove entries from the <guilabel>Default Policies</guilabel> tab?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            <guilabel>Default Policies</guilabel> ensure that all possible types of traffic are handled by the Virtual Racks.
          </para>
          <para>
            If you were allowed to delete a Default Policy and you did not add a Custom Policy that is the equivalent of the Default Policy that you deleted, the &eg; would be unable to handle some types of traffic.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>    
    
      <!-- ******************************************* -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>I only want to scan inbound email traffic, not outbound.  Do I need to create a new Virtual Rack and Policies?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            No.  Many Software Appliances (including all of those which scan email) let you directly configure behaviors for <constant>inbound</constant> vs. <constant>outbound</constant> traffic.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>

      <!-- ******************************************* -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>
            We are using the &eg; with its VPN Software Appliance.  Do I need to create extra Virtual Racks/Policies for the VPN users?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            You do not have to create extra Virtual Racks/Policies to use VPN.  The <constant>VPN</constant> interface is, by default, inside the <constant>external</constant> and <constant>DMZ</constant> interfaces, but outside of the <constant>internal</constant> interface.  The single <constant>Default Rack</constant> is sufficient for most deployments.
          </para>
          <para>
            One case where you would need to create extra Virtual Racks/Policies is when not all VPN users are equal and you want to apply different rules to different VPN users.  If all VPN users are equal, have the Policies dealing with the VPN interface route traffic to the <constant>Default Rack</constant>.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>      

