      <!-- ******************************************* -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>Why can't I add/remove entries from the <guilabel>Default Policies</guilabel> tab?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            The default policies ensure that all possible traffic is handled by a Virtual Rack.  Deleting one of these entries without a corresponding entry in the <guilabel>Custom Policies</guilabel> tab would cause the &eg; not to know how to handle some types of traffic.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>    
    
      <!-- ******************************************* -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>I only want to scan inbound email traffic, not outbound.  Do I need to create a new Virtual Rack and Policies?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            No.  Many Software Appliances (including all of those which scan email) let you directly configure behaviors for <constant>inbound</constant> vs. <constant>outbound</constant> traffic.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>

      <!-- ******************************************* -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>We are using the &eg; with its VPN Software Appliance.  Do I need to configure extra Virtual Racks for the VPN users?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            You do not have to create extra Virtual Racks/Policies in order to use VPN.  The <constant>VPN</constant> interface is, by default, inside the <constant>external</constant> and <constant>DNZ</constant> interfaces, but outside of the <constant>internal</constant> interface.  The single <constant>Default Rack</constant> is correct for most deployments.
          </para>
          <para>
            One situation where you would need to do so if you want to scan traffic  <emphasis>differently</emphasis> for different VPN users.  If you consider all VPN users are equivalent, just route the Policies dealing with the VPN interface to <constant>Default Rack</constant>.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>      
