  <!-- ========================================================= -->  
  <sect1 id="config_tab_accounts">
    <title>Accounts</title>
    <para>
      The Accounts Tab, as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_accounts_figure"/>, is used to add/modify administrator accounts.  Administrators are users who are able to use the Administrative Console.  This is not to be confused with end-users (people who browse the web, receive email, etc) who do not need logins to the &eg;.
    </para>

    <figure id="config_tab_accounts_figure">
      <title>Accounts Tab</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="figure/configtab/config_tab_accounts.png" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
      There are three actions one would take with the Accounts Tab: adding an administrator, removing an administrator, or changing an administrator's password.  Each of these actions are detailed as follows.  Note that one or more of these action may be taken, but do not take effect into the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button is pushed.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <title>Common Administrative Actions</title>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Adding an Account</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            To add an account, push the add (plus) button to the left of the panel.  This adds a new (blank) row to the table.  The <guilabel>name</guilabel> column is a descriptive name, such as <quote>Emma Scott</quote> or <quote>Jun Wang</quote>.  The <guilabel>login</guilabel> column is a login name, such as <quote>escott</quote> or <quote>jwang</quote>.  
          </para>
          <para>
            The next two columns, <guilabel>set new password</guilabel> and <guilabel>confirm new password</guilabel>, should be populated with the new Administrator's password.  Both fields need to be filled with the same password.  The next field is <guilabel>original user's password</guilabel>.  When adding a new user, <emphasis>this field is automatically populated.  Do not change the default value.</emphasis>  The past field is for the new Administrator's email address.  It may be left blank.
          </para>
          <para>
            The new account will become active once the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button is pushed.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Removing an Administrator</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            To remove an administrator account, highlight the account (row) to be deleted then push the remove (minus) button to the left.  You must then enter the account about to be deleted's password in the <guilabel>original user's password</guilabel>.  The account will be removed once the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button is pushed.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Changing a Password</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            To change the password for an administrative account, highlight the account (row) of the account to change.  Then enter the new password into the <guilabel>set new password</guilabel> and <guilabel>confirm new password</guilabel> fields.  The existing (current) password must then be entered into the <guilabel>original user's password</guilabel> field.
          </para>
          <para>
            The password change will take effect once the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button is pushed.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>    
    </variablelist>
    
  </sect1>