  

  <!-- ========================================================= -->  
  <sect1 id="config_tab_network_settings">
    <title>Network Settings</title>
    <para>
      The Networking Settings panel controls several global networking-related properties of your &eg;.  Refer to the three subsections, <xref linkend="config_tab_network_networksettings"/>, <xref linkend="config_tab_network_email"/>, and <xref linkend="config_tab_network_networkaliases"/> for more details.
    </para>

    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="config_tab_network_networksettings">
      <title>Network Settings</title>
      <para>
        The Network Settings Tab, as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_network_networksettings_figure"/>, lets administrators control how their &eg; appears to the outside (non-protected) network.
      </para>
      <figure id="config_tab_network_networksettings_figure">
        <title>Network Settings Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/configtab/config_tab_network_networksettings.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The &eg; can be set-up to either have a <glossterm linkend="gloss_static_ip">static</glossterm> or dynamic IP address.  For a static IP, administrators must configure the network settings as they would for any system on the network.  Dynamic addresses are obtained from <glossterm linkend="gloss_dhcp">DHCP</glossterm>.
      </para>
      <para>
        The interface for configuring these external settings is divided into three sections.  The first section determines if the &eg; is using a static or dynamic address.  To choose between these options, the administrator selects either <guilabel>Automatically Set</guilabel> or <guilabel>Manually Set</guilabel>.  If <guilabel>Automatically Set</guilabel> is selected, the &eg; will use DHCP to obtain network settings and display them in the boxes below.  If <guilabel>Manually Set</guilabel> is selected, the administrator must manually set the <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP Address</glossterm>, <glossterm linkend="gloss_netmask">Netmask</glossterm>, <glossterm linkend="gloss_default_route">Default Route</glossterm> (sometimes referred to as <quote>gateway</quote>), as well as a primary <glossterm linkend="gloss_dns">DNS</glossterm> server and a secondary DNS server (optional).
      </para>
      <para>
        Should <guilabel>Automatically Set</guilabel> be selected, then administrators can optionally request a renewal of their <glossterm linkend="gloss_dhcp_lease">DHCP Lease</glossterm> via the <guilabel>Renew DHCP Lease</guilabel> button.  This is the second section as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_network_networksettings_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <para>
        Whether <guilabel>Automatically Set</guilabel> or <guilabel>Manually Set</guilabel> is selected for the external interface, the <guilabel>Run Connectivity Test</guilabel> button can be used to perform a test of these settings.  This is the third section as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_network_networksettings_figure"/>.  Activating the test will then report its findings (success/failure).
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="config_tab_network_email">
      <title>Email Settings</title>
      <para>
        The Email Settings tab, as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_network_email_figure"/>, lets administrators control how &eg; sends emails.
      </para>
      <figure id="config_tab_network_email_figure">
        <title>Email Settings Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/configtab/config_tab_network_email.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The &eg; sends emails for several reasons.  Various Software Appliances (for example, <link linkend="clam_tran">Virus Scanning</link>) will send end-users emails informing them of malicious payloads such as viruses.  The <link linkend="config_tab_quarantine">Quarantine</link> feature sends users a daily digest of the spams they received, and the <link linkend="reporting_tran">EdgeGuard Reports Appliance</link> sends daily summary reports to administrators about their &eg; activity.
      </para>
      <para>
        The interface for configuring the email settings (as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_network_email_figure"/>) requires two properties for normal mail traffic.  The first property, <guilabel>Hostname</guilabel>, is the name of your <glossterm linkend="gloss_smtp">SMTP</glossterm> mail server (e.g. <constant>mail.mycompany.com</constant> or <constant>4.79.181.14</constant>).  The second property is <guilabel>port</guilabel>.  The standard port for sending email via SMTP is <constant>25</constant>.  You should only change this setting if you know your mail server is using a non-standard port.
      </para>
      <para>
        For sites using authenticated SMTP (SMTP which requires a username and password), the <guilabel>Authentication Login</guilabel> and <guilabel>Authentication Password</guilabel> fields should be set.  Otherwise, these can be safely left blank.
      </para>
      <para>
        The final property, <guilabel>From Address</guilabel>, provides a <quote>FROM</quote> value for emails sent from &eg;.  
      </para>
    </sect2>


    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="config_tab_network_timezone">
      <title>Timezone</title>
      <para>
        The Timezone for your &eg; is set as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_network_timezone_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="config_tab_network_timezone_figure">
        <title>Timezone Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/configtab/config_tab_network_timezone.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        Administrators should select the timezone where the &eg; is deployed.
      </para>
    </sect2>     

    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="config_tab_network_networkaliases">
      <title>Network Aliases</title>
      <para>
        The Network Aliases tab, as seen in, <xref linkend="config_tab_network_networkaliases_figure"/>, is for complex &eg; deployments.
      </para>
      <figure id="config_tab_network_networkaliases_figure">
        <title>Network Aliases Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/configtab/config_tab_network_networkaliases.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        Use of this feature depends on if the &eg; is providing <glossterm linkend="gloss_nat">NAT</glossterm> services to the internal (protected) network.  If running NAT (see <xref linkend="nat_tran"/>), then this feature can be used to receive traffic for more than just the network of the &eg;'s external interface.
      </para>
      <para>
        If your &eg; is not running NAT (sometimes called <quote>bridge</quote> mode), then each addition to the Network Aliases will allow &eg; to route traffic for networks other than that defined by its external IP address.
      </para>
    </sect2>    
    
  </sect1> 

