
      <!-- ************************************************************** -->
      <qandaentry id="config_tab_q1">
        <question>
          <para>What is the IP address of my &eg; from within the protected network?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            The internal IP address depends on how the &eg; is configured.  If configured for Network Sharing (NAT), then the internal IP is set within the Network Sharing Software Appliance (see <xref linkend="nat_tran"/>).  If the &eg; is not configured for NAT (sometimes called <quote>bridge</quote> mode), then the internal IP is the same as the external IP.  The external IP can be seen from the Networking Settings interface, as described in <xref linkend="config_tab_network_networksettings"/>.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>

      
      <!-- ************************************************************** -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>What is the IP address of my &eg; from outside the protected network?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            The address from outside the protected network (called the <quote>external IP</quote>) can be found/changed on the Networking Settings interface, as described in <xref linkend="config_tab_network_networksettings"/>.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>

      
      <!-- ************************************************************** -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>Someone left our company, but we still receives emails.  Since some of those emails are Spam, how can I prevent their inbox from growing forever?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            The &eg; does not know valid from invalid email addresses within your domain.  The easiest way to prevent emails for an ex-employee is to configure your mail server to reject those mails.
          </para>
          <para>
            If causing emails to be rejected is not an option (for example, emails from business partners are still being received and must be reviewed during the transition) then Spam emails can simply be ignored.  Recall that the system automatically deletes emails from inboxes after a fixed period (see <xref linkend="config_tab_quarantine_general"/> for more details on this setting).  Note that once emails for that user cease, the inbox will automatically be deleted after two months of inactivity.  
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>      

      
      <!-- ************************************************************** -->   
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>Looking at the Quarantine interface, I cannot find how to cause Spam-suspect emails to be quarantined.  How do I configure this?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            The Quarantine feature is used by several Software Appliances.  The interfaces for each appliance is used to cause emails to be quarantined.  Please see <xref linkend="spamassassin_tran"/> for more information on configuring SpamGuard and <xref linkend="clamphish_tran"/> for configuring PhishNet to use the Quarantine feature.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      

      <!-- ************************************************************** -->
      <qandaentry>
        <question>
          <para>One of my users deleted all of their daily quarantine digest emails, yet they want to check their inbox right now.  How can I cause them to receive a new digest on demand?</para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            If an end-user wants to view their inbox <quote>right now</quote> yet lacks a digest email with the links to do so, they can request a new digest email.  The <glossterm linkend="gloss_url">URL</glossterm> for this request page is

            <programlisting>http://<replaceable>your_internal_ip</replaceable>/quarantine/requestdigest</programlisting>

            Where <replaceable>your_internal_ip</replaceable> is replaced with the internal <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr">IP address</glossterm> of your &eg;.  To determine the internal IP address of your &eg;, please refer to <xref linkend="config_tab_q1"/>
          </para>
          <tip>
            <para>
              This URL to request a digest email on-demand will not change as long as the internal IP address of &eg; does not change.  It may be handy to put a link to this page on an intranet server.
            </para>
          </tip>
       </answer>
      </qandaentry> 
