

  <!-- ========================================================= -->  
  <sect1 id="config_tab_remote_admin">
    <title>Remote Administration</title>

    <para>
      The Remote Administration tab controls settings for the Administrative Interface itself (who can/cannot administer the &eg;) as well as remote monitoring.
    </para>


    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="config_tab_remoteadmin_remoteadmin">
      <title>Remote Administration</title>
      <para>
        The Remote Administration tab, as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_remoteadmin_remoteadmin_figure"/>, lets Administrators control how the Administrative Interface can be used.
      </para>
      <figure id="config_tab_remoteadmin_remoteadmin_figure">
        <title>Remote Administration Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/configtab/config_tab_remoteadmin_remoteadmin.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    <para>
      <emphasis>External</emphasis> administration is defined as someone accessing the Administrative Interface from outside the protected network.  <emphasis>Internal</emphasis> administration is someone accessing the Administrative Interface from within the protected network.  Someone from the <glossterm linkend="gloss_dmz">DMZ</glossterm> is considered <emphasis>external</emphasis>.
      <note>
        <para>
          The current external IP address can be found from the <link linkend="config_tab_network_networksettings">Network Settings</link> panel.  If the &eg; is running <glossterm linkend="gloss_nat">NAT</glossterm>, the internal IP can be found from the NAT settings as explained in <xref linkend="nat_tran"/>.  If the system is not running NAT, then the internal IP is the same as the external IP.
        </para>
      </note>
      We will now discuss the details of configuring the &eg; for external and internal administration.
    </para>
    <simplesect>
      <title><guilabel>External Remote Administration</guilabel></title>
      <para>
        External administration can be enabled/disabled by selecting either the <guilabel>Allow</guilabel> or <guilabel>Deny</guilabel> options within the External Remote Administration section.  Note that if enabled, <emphasis>all administration traffic is passed over a secure (SSL) connection</emphasis>.
      </para>
      <para>
        If administration from outside the protected network is enabled, Administrators can also choose to restrict administration from a select set of machines.  This restriction is set by first selecting <guilabel>Restrict</guilabel> then populating the <glossterm linkend="gloss_ip_addr"><guilabel>IP Address</guilabel></glossterm> and <glossterm linkend="gloss_netmask"><guilabel>Netmask</guilabel></glossterm> fields.
      </para>
    </simplesect>
    <simplesect>
      <title><guilabel>Internal Remote Administration</guilabel></title>
      <para>
        Internal administration can be configured to require an encrypted (SSL) connection or not.  To require an SSL connection, select the <guilabel>Disallow</guilabel> option under <guilabel>Internal Remote Administration</guilabel>.  Note that secure remote administration is <emphasis>always</emphasis> enabled from the internal network.
      </para>
    </simplesect>

      
    </sect2>


    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="config_tab_remoteadmin_snmp">
      <title>SNMP Monitoring</title>
      <para>
        The <glossterm linkend="gloss_snmp">SNMP</glossterm> Monitoring tab, as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_remoteadmin_snmp_figure"/>, controls how &eg; uses SNMP.
      </para>
      <figure id="config_tab_remoteadmin_snmp_figure">
        <title>SNMP Monitoring Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/configtab/config_tab_remoteadmin_snmp.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The &eg; is able to respond to read-only SNMP queries.  It exports MIB-II (see RFC 1213), as well as (optionally) sends <glossterm linkend="gloss_trap">traps</glossterm>.  To enable the &eg; to field SNMP queries, select the <guilabel>Enable SNMP Monitoring</guilabel> option as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_remoteadmin_snmp_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <para>
        If <guilabel>Enable SNMP Monitoring</guilabel> is selected, three additional pieces of information should be provided.  The first is the <guilabel>Community</guilabel>, which is used in SNMP v1 to authenticate queries.
        <warning>
          <para>
            Be sure to change the default community value when enabling this feature
          </para>
        </warning>
        The next two fields are <guilabel>System Contact</guilabel> and <guilabel>System Location</guilabel>.  Although not required for normal operation, they greatly assist in troubleshooting.  They should be populated with contact information and the physical location of the &eg; (respectively).
      </para>
      <para>
        The &eg; can also be configured to send warm and cold start traps.  To enable the sending of traps, select <guilabel>Enable Traps</guilabel> at the bottom of the SNMP Monitoring tab.  You must then provide a host/port (via the <guilabel>Host</guilabel> and <guilabel>Port</guilabel> respectively).  The field <guilabel>Community</guilabel> must be populated with the community string for the trap-receiving server.
        <note>
          <para>
            Not all SNMP trap receiver tools require a community string.  If your tool does not require a community string, the <guilabel>Community</guilabel> field can be left blank.
          </para>
        </note>
      </para>
    </sect2>


    <!-- ====================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="config_tab_remoteadmin_syslog">
      <title>Syslog Monitoring</title>
      <para>
        Syslog Monitoring, as seen in <xref linkend="config_tab_remoteadmin_syslog_figure"/>, allows Administrators to redirect information from the &eg; to a <glossterm linkend="gloss_syslog">Syslog</glossterm> server.
      </para>
      <figure id="config_tab_remoteadmin_syslog_figure">
        <title>Syslog Monitoring Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/configtab/config_tab_remoteadmin_syslog.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>
        From the Syslog Monitoring tab, Administrators can enable/disable their &eg; from sending Syslog messages via selecting either <guilabel>Disable Syslog Monitoring</guilabel> or <guilabel>Enable Syslog Monitoring</guilabel>.  If <guilabel>Enable Syslog Monitoring</guilabel> is selected, further information is required for this feature to function.
      </para>
      <para>
        The <guilabel>Host</guilabel> field is the name of the server running a Syslog server.  This server should be configured to allow remote submission of Syslog messages.  The next field is <guilabel>Port</guilabel>, and should only be changed from the standard port (512) should the Syslog server be listening on a non-standard port.
      </para>
      <para>
        <guilabel>Facility</guilabel> is the Syslog facility for which &eg; messages will be submitted.  The <guilabel>Facility</guilabel> contains all standard Syslog values for <constant>facility</constant>.  <guilabel>Threshold</guilabel> is the minimum Syslog threshold, such that &eg; will not send messages below this level.  Note that &eg; sends messages at the <constant>informational</constant>, <constant>notice</constant> and <constant>warning</constant> levels.  In general, messages indicating traffic was inspected and found not to contain questionable content is sent as <constant>informational</constant>.  Inspected traffic which required &eg; to take action (for example, blocking a restricted web page) is sent as <constant>notice</constant>.  The exception to this last case is for viruses found, which are sent as <constant>warning</constant> messages.
      </para>
      
    </sect2>           
    
  </sect1> 
