<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="httpblocker_tran">

  <title>Web Content Control</title>

  <para>
    The Web Content Control is identified by the
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="figure/httpblocker/httpblocker_tran_icon.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
    symbol.  If the Web Content Control Appliance is not installed, please refer to <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances"/> for installation instructions.
  </para>
  <para>
    As its name implies, the Web Content Control Appliance is used to filter web traffic to your protected network for inappropriate content.  Unlike other software appliances, the the criteria used by the Web Content Control Appliance can be seen as subjective.  Inappropriate content may be executables to some, while to others it is web sites discussing Illegal Drugs.  
  </para>

  <sect1 id="httpblocker_tran_adminui">
    <title>Administrative Interface</title>

    <para>
      The interface for the Web Content Control is presented as three tabs.  The first two tabs, covered in sections <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block"/> and <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_pass"/>, allow control over blocked and permitted content.   The last tab, discussed in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_eventlog"/>, allows administrators to view events.
    </para>
    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="httpblocker_tran_block">
      <title>Block Lists</title>
      <para>
        The Block List tab presents administrators the ability to modify the four major criteria of content filtering: by category, URL, MIME Type and File Extension.  Refer to the section for each sub-tab for more detail.
      </para>
  
      <!-- ############################################################## -->
      <sect3 id="httpblocker_tran_block_categories">
        <title>Categories</title>
        <para>
          The Categories tab, as shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_categories_figure"/>, allows the administrator the ability to block categories of sites.  The names of the various categories and a description are presented in the table.
        </para>
        <figure id="httpblocker_tran_block_categories_figure">
          <title>Categories Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/httpblocker/httpblocker_block_categories.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          When a user within the protected network browses a site selected in the Category tab, they will be presented with an error page.  The page will inform the user that their request has been blocked by the Web Content Control Appliance.  They will also be told the category (<quote>Web Mail</quote>, <quote>Gambling</quote>, etc) of the site in question.
        </para>
      </sect3>
  
      <!-- ############################################################## -->
      <sect3 id="httpblocker_tran_block_urls">
        <title>URLs</title>
        <para>
          The block list of <glossterm linkend="gloss_url">URLs</glossterm> is shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_urls_figure"/>
        </para>        
        <figure id="httpblocker_tran_block_urls_figure">
          <title>URLs Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/httpblocker/httpblocker_block_urls.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          The URL block list is initially empty.  When adding a new entry, you enter a URL which encompasses an exact match or any URLs matching that prefix (see <xref linkend="appendix_syntax_urlmatcher"/> for more details on URL matching).  The <guilabel>category</guilabel> column can contain any category of your choosing (it does not have to correspond to the predefined categories discussed in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_categories"/>).
        </para>           
      </sect3>
  
      <!-- ############################################################## -->
      <sect3 id="httpblocker_tran_block_mime">
        <title>MIME Types</title>
        <para>
          The <glossterm linkend="gloss_mime_type">MIME Types</glossterm> tab lets administrators block the downloading of content by MIME type.  The interface for the MIME Types tab is shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_mime_figure"/>.
        </para>
        <figure id="httpblocker_tran_block_mime_figure">
          <title>MIME Types Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/httpblocker/httpblocker_block_mime.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          As shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_mime_figure"/>, the list contains the most common MIME types.  By default, they are no MIME types blocked.  To block a particular MIME Type, check the <guilabel>block</guilabel> box.
        </para>
      </sect3>
  
      <!-- ############################################################## -->
      <sect3 id="httpblocker_tran_block_fileext">
        <title>File Extensions</title>
        <para>
          The File Extensions Tab, as shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_fileext_figure"/>, allows Administrators to cause the download of files to be blocked based on file extension (e.g. .exe).
        </para>
        <figure id="httpblocker_tran_block_fileext_figure">
          <title>File Extensions Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/httpblocker/httpblocker_block_fileext.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          As shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_fileext_figure"/>, the list contains the most common file extensions.  No file extensions are blocked by default.  To block a file extension, check the <guilabel>block</guilabel> box.
        </para>        
      </sect3>          
    </sect2>
  
    <!-- ======================================================== -->  
    <sect2 id="httpblocker_tran_pass">
      <title>Pass Lists</title>
      <para>
        As discussed in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block"/>, the Web Content Control Appliance offers several ways to block inappropriate or malicious traffic from entering your protected network.  However, there may be circumstances where you need to bypass these guards for an individual within your company, or a site outside your network.
      </para>
      <para>
        The Pass List allows individuals and groups to bypass filtering.  When traffic is found to <quote>match</quote> an entry in one of the pass lists, it is <emphasis>not</emphasis> filtered.  Passes can be created for various sites, as discussed in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_pass_urls"/>, or for individual machines within the protected network as discussed in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_pass_clients"/>.
      </para>
  
      <!-- ############################################################## -->
      <sect3 id="httpblocker_tran_pass_urls">
        <title>URLs</title>
        <para>
          The pass list of <glossterm linkend="gloss_url">URLs</glossterm> is shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_pass_urls_figure"/>
        </para>
        <figure id="httpblocker_tran_pass_urls_figure">
          <title>URLs Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/httpblocker/httpblocker_pass_urls.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          The URL pass list is initially empty.  When adding a new entry, you enter a URL which encompasses an exact match or any URLs matching that prefix (see <xref linkend="appendix_syntax_urlmatcher"/> for more details on URL matching).  The <guilabel>category</guilabel> column can contain any category of your choosing (it does not have to correspond to the predefined categories discussed in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_categories"/>).
        </para>
      </sect3>
  
      <!-- ############################################################## -->
      <sect3 id="httpblocker_tran_pass_clients">
        <title>Clients</title>
        <para>
          The <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_pass_urls"/> lets Administrators define sites outside the protected network which will not receive filtering.  The Clients Tab lets Administrators define machines <emphasis>within</emphasis> the protected network whose requests will not be filtered.  The interface for the client pass list is shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_pass_clients_figure"/>.
        </para>
        <figure id="httpblocker_tran_pass_clients_figure">
          <title>Clients Tab</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="figure/httpblocker/httpblocker_pass_clients.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          The list shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_pass_clients_figure"/> is initially empty.  As new entries are made, administrators must enter <guilabel>client IP address</guilabel>.  The format of the  <guilabel>client IP address</guilabel> field is either in <link linkend="appendix_syntax_simpleipaddr">Simple IP Address</link> or <link linkend="appendix_syntax_networknetmask">Network/Netmask</link> format.  Note that the <guilabel>category</guilabel> field is only for administrator reference - it need not match up with the predefined categories discussed in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_block_categories"/>.
        </para>
      </sect3>    
    </sect2>
  
    <!-- ======================================================== -->
    <sect2 id="httpblocker_tran_eventlog">
      <title>Event Log</title>
      <para>
        The Events tab contents is shown in <xref linkend="httpblocker_tran_eventlog_figure"/>.
      </para>
      <figure id="httpblocker_tran_eventlog_figure">
        <title> Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="figure/httpblocker/httpblocker_eventlog.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Events Tab is another implementation of an Event Log, as described in <xref linkend="using_adminui_appliances_eventlog"/>.  The <guilabel>action</guilabel> column describes the action which the &eg; took on the web request.  The <guilabel>client</guilabel> column shows the IP address of the client who made the request.
      </para>        
    </sect2>  
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="httpblocker_tran_qa">
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaset>  

      &httpblocker_tran_qa;
       
    </qandaset>
  </sect1>  
  

</chapter>

